

nickvaccaro.com njvaccaro0@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/NickJVaccaro

I'm a professional programmer with 11 years of experience, the last 3 of which I've spent working on a live MMORPG built with Unity, C#, & Java. Before that, I co-founded a gamedev company and worked as a Full-Stack Web Developer (React, C#, JavaScript, SQL). I'm used to small teams and wearing many hats, with an affinity for the developing, project managing, and QA hats. I'm focused on results, and do whatever I can to help the entire team succeed.

# Work Experience

#### **Game Programmer** | Elder Game LLC

2/2021 - Present

- Revamped a core interface, the targeting UI, from design to implementation and iteration based on internal and player feedback
- Implemented dozens of QoL improvements, both self-directed and player-submitted. Primary areas of focus were UI (Inventory, Quest, Skills, Crafting), Animations, VFX, & Optimizations
- Tackled hundreds of player-submitted bugs for both front-end and back-end, often interacting with players on our public Discord to gather additional info & provide bugfix updates
- Assisted with monitoring & hotfixing dozens of patches
- Performed internet-wide player research to determine development priorities

### Game Programmer / Producer / Co-Founder | Synersteel Studio

8/2015 - Present

- Currently developing Valley of Shadow, a story-heavy puzzle game.
  - o Responsible for all programming (Unity/C#), puzzle design, project management, & QA
  - o Presented at PAX East, Tiny Teams, & Cerebral Puzzle Showcase
  - Created and maintain Steam page, including regular build uploads and patch notes
- Periodically launch games and patches on 3 storefronts: iTunes, Google Play, & Steam
- Optimize games to run smoothly across all platforms: PC, Mac, iOS, and Android
- Released 4 video games to market, working with a different client for each game, all in Unity

#### Senior Software Developer | Privakey, Inc.

5/2019 - 9/2021

- Built admin portal in ReactJS + Redux to interact with backend, with 30+ components
- Designed & implemented React Native app with native Android library, with 10+ pages
- Led dev team as Scrum Master, ensuring regular Sprint meetings, QA, and code reviews

### Software Developer / Project Manager | Privakey, Inc.

1/2016 - 7/2018

- Architected, implemented, and publicly documented an OpenID auth server with dozens of secure API routes using Test-Driven Development with .NET (C#), MySQL, and Postman
- Built a fully responsive admin portal to interface with auth server in Angular|S
- Promoted to part-time Project Manager while continuing to develop the software

#### **Software Developer** | *Probaris Technologies*

9/2012 - 1/2016

- Developed web applications to manage identity credentials with ASP.NET (C#)
- Integrated software with physical fingerprint scanners in .NET
- Created and modified web services in .NET and Java

## Skills

# Education

**Languages** C#, Java, SQL, JavaScript, HTML/CSS **Frameworks** .NET, NodeJS, ReactJS, React Native, Angular **Tools** Unity, AWS, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Git, SVN **Drexel University**B.S. in Computer Engineering
2007 - 2012